[
	{
		"answerText": "cogito ergo sum [or I am thinking, therefore I am; prompt on the cogito][10] This French dualist philosopher who wrote Discourse on Method declared cogito ergo sum. He questioned the veracity of our senses with scenarios involving melting wax and an evil demon.",
		"prompts": [
			"cogito",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"dualist",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"wrote",
			"Discourse",
			"Method",
			"declared",
			"cogito",
			"ergo",
			"sum",
			"He",
			"questioned",
			"veracity",
			"our",
			"senses",
			"with",
			"scenarios",
			"involving",
			"melting",
			"wax",
			"and",
			"an",
			"evil",
			"demon"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 04 | 1 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Nietzsche and Kierkegaard criticized this proposition because its first statement presupposes self-existence. For 10 points each:  [10] Identify this proposition concluding self-existence that for one philosopher, serves as the basis for all further knowledge. It was reached by indirect proof after a process of hyperbolic doubt in Discourse on Method. ",
		"answers": [
			"cogito",
			"ergo",
			"sum",
			"I",
			"am",
			"thinking",
			"therefore"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Leviathan[10] The Leviathan is a political structure imagined by this English philosopher, who warned that the alternative is a state of nature where life is \"solitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 16 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This entity is depicted wielding both a sword and a papal staff with a body made of people. For 10 points each: [10] Identify this symbol of the Commonwealth, headed by a Sovereign with civil and ecclesiastical power. It represents a covenant where people cede their natural rights for a state of peace. ",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Leviathan",
			"10",
			"The",
			"political",
			"structure",
			"imagined",
			"by",
			"this",
			"English",
			"philosopher",
			"who",
			"warned",
			"that",
			"alternative",
			"state",
			"nature",
			"where",
			"life",
			"solitary",
			"poor",
			"nasty",
			"brutish",
			"and",
			"short"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "anarchy[10] Thucydides fictionalized a dialogue between realist Athens and this idealist island during the Peloponnesian War. This island refuses to surrender to the Athenians, who justify its destruction wih \"might makes right\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 12 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, identify the following about realism in international relations. [10] Realists believe that the international system is characterized by this property, since it lacks a universal central authority. Because of this, uncertainty and self-help pervade the system.",
		"answers": [
			"anarchy",
			"10",
			"Thucydides",
			"fictionalized",
			"dialogue",
			"between",
			"realist",
			"Athens",
			"and",
			"this",
			"idealist",
			"island",
			"during",
			"Peloponnesian",
			"War",
			"This",
			"refuses",
			"to",
			"surrender",
			"Athenians",
			"who",
			"justify",
			"its",
			"destruction",
			"wih",
			"might",
			"makes",
			"right"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "being [or Sein][10] Martin Heidegger, the author of Being and Time, was a forerunner of this movement most notably espoused by Jacques Derrida in Of Grammatology. This form of criticism believes that there is \"nothing outside the text.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BISB |2013 | 2 | 10 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This phenomenon occurs \"toward-death\" and \"in-the-world\", and one form of it is defined as \"this entity which each of us is himself.\" For 10 points each [10] Name this central concept of dasein (pr. DIE-ZIN). This word is paired with \"time\" in the title of a 1927 work of philosophy.",
		"answers": [
			"being",
			"Sein",
			"10",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"author",
			"Being",
			"and",
			"Time",
			"was",
			"forerunner",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"most"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "syllogism[10] In order to get the upper hand, your partner remarks, \"Well, you've got a terrible sense of taste, and you have big feet.\" Such irrelevant, personal attacks, are often described by this two-word Latin phrase.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Brookwood Invitational Scholars Bowl |2013 | 1 | 8 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: You are arguing that all M&Ms don't have the same flavor with a terrible arguer who thinks they do. For 10 points each: [10] Your adversary claims, \"All M&Ms are made of chocolate, and all chocolate has the same flavor, therefore all M&Ms have the same flavor\"--an example of these three-part statements first described by Aristotle.",
		"answers": [
			"syllogism",
			"10",
			"In",
			"order",
			"to",
			"get",
			"upper",
			"hand",
			"your",
			"partner",
			"remarks",
			"Well",
			"you've",
			"got",
			"terrible",
			"sense",
			"taste",
			"and",
			"you",
			"have",
			"big",
			"feet",
			"Such",
			"irrelevant",
			"personal",
			"attacks",
			"are",
			"often",
			"described",
			"by",
			"this",
			"two-word",
			"Latin",
			"phrase"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Birth of Tragedy from the Spirit of Music [accept Die Geburt der Tragödie aus dem Geiste der Musik][10] This work by the same author of The Birth of Tragedy first introduced the concept of the Übermensch, which is described as the ultimate goal for humanity.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 18 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This work was later reissued by its author with an additional preface, An Attempt at Self-Criticism. For 10 points each: [10] Name this work which contrasts the Apollonian and Dionysian interpretations of a certain art form.",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Birth",
			"Tragedy",
			"from",
			"Spirit",
			"Music",
			"Die",
			"Geburt",
			"der",
			"Tragödie",
			"aus",
			"dem",
			"Geiste",
			"Musik",
			"10",
			"This",
			"work",
			"by",
			"same",
			"author",
			"first",
			"introduced",
			"concept",
			"Übermensch",
			"which",
			"described",
			"as",
			"ultimate",
			"goal",
			"for",
			"humanity"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Immanuel Kant[10] This philosopher gave a critique of Kant in the work Kant and the Problem of Metaphysics. This Nazi supporter proposed the concept of Dasein, or \"existence,\" in Being and Time.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 18 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This philosopher encouraged others to \"dare to know\" in his work \"What is Enlightenment?\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this German philosopher who examined a priori knowledge in his Critique of Pure Reason.",
		"answers": [
			"Immanuel",
			"Kant",
			"10",
			"This",
			"philosopher",
			"gave",
			"critique",
			"in",
			"work",
			"and",
			"Problem",
			"Metaphysics",
			"Nazi",
			"supporter",
			"proposed",
			"concept",
			"Dasein",
			"existence",
			"Being",
			"Time"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Karl Heinrich Marx[10] Marx is known for this multi-volume treatise, which posits that the tendency of the rate of profit to fall leads to the exploitation of labor by employers to produce the title asset.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 5 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man claimed that \"[s]ociety does not consist of individuals, but expresses the sum of interrelations, the relations within which these individuals stand.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this man, whose writings inspired the theory of historical materialism.",
		"answers": [
			"Karl",
			"Heinrich",
			"Marx",
			"10",
			"known",
			"for",
			"this",
			"multi-volume",
			"treatise",
			"which",
			"posits",
			"that",
			"tendency",
			"rate",
			"profit",
			"to",
			"fall",
			"leads",
			"exploitation",
			"labor",
			"by",
			"employers",
			"produce",
			"title",
			"asset"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Principia Mathematica[10] This British thinker wrote Principia Mathematica along with Alfred Whitehead; other works by him include \"A History of Western Philosophy\" and \"Why I am not a Christian.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 12 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This work attempted to derive a set of axioms that could be used to prove mathematical truths. For 10 points each: [10] Name this work of set theory and mathematical logic that was shown to have failed to fulfill its goal by Gödel's Incompleteness Theorems. ",
		"answers": [
			"Principia",
			"Mathematica",
			"10",
			"This",
			"British",
			"thinker",
			"wrote",
			"along",
			"with",
			"Alfred",
			"Whitehead",
			"other",
			"works",
			"by",
			"him",
			"include",
			"A",
			"History",
			"Western",
			"Philosophy",
			"and",
			"Why",
			"I",
			"am"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Friedrich Nietzsche[10] In The Birth of Tragedy Nietzsche compares the more chaotic art of Dionysus to the art of this god, which is guided more by reason.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 6 | 20 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: His book Ecce Homo contains chapters titled \"Why I Am So Wise\" and \"Why I Am a Destiny.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this German philosopher who said \"God is dead\" and related concepts like the ubermensch in his book Thus Spake Zarathustra.",
		"answers": [
			"Friedrich",
			"Nietzsche",
			"10",
			"In",
			"The",
			"Birth",
			"Tragedy",
			"compares",
			"more",
			"chaotic",
			"art",
			"Dionysus",
			"to",
			"this",
			"god",
			"which",
			"guided",
			"by",
			"reason"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Confucianism (accept word forms including Confucius)[10] This collection of Confucius's sayings was compiled by his followers, and includes his descriptions of concepts such as the Golden Rule.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 9 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Mencius was one member of this school of thought. For 10 points each: [10] Name this philosophy formulated by a namesake Chinese philosopher which advocates filial piety. It was the state philosophy of the Han dynasty.",
		"answers": [
			"Confucianism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"including",
			"Confucius",
			"10",
			"This",
			"collection",
			"Confucius's",
			"sayings",
			"was",
			"compiled",
			"by",
			"his",
			"followers",
			"and",
			"includes",
			"descriptions",
			"concepts",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Golden",
			"Rule"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mohism [or Mojia][10] The Mohist theory of \"impartial care\" is often translated as the \"Universal\" type of this emotion, which is discussed drunkenly in Plato's Symposium.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 5 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  This school sought objective moral standards called fa, and followed ten doctrines such as \"Thrift in Funerals\" which were laid out in ten triads of essays. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this Chinese school of thought which was opposed to Confucianism for its lack of concern with filial piety. It was wiped out by Legalism. ",
		"answers": [
			"Mohism",
			"Mojia",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Mohist",
			"theory",
			"impartial",
			"care",
			"often",
			"translated",
			"as",
			"Universal",
			"type",
			"this",
			"emotion",
			"which",
			"discussed",
			"drunkenly",
			"in",
			"Plato's",
			"Symposium"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Baruch Spinoza[10]  Spinoza's monism contrasts with this theory that asserts that the mind is an independently existing but non-physical substance. It was developed by Rene Descartes.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round01.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This philosopher approached the mind-body problem with the assertion that everything that exists, including human beings, is a \"mode\" of God, a theory that he espoused in his work Ethics.",
		"answers": [
			"Baruch",
			"Spinoza",
			"10",
			"Spinoza's",
			"monism",
			"contrasts",
			"with",
			"this",
			"theory",
			"that",
			"asserts",
			"mind",
			"an",
			"independently",
			"existing",
			"but",
			"non-physical",
			"substance",
			"It",
			"was",
			"developed",
			"by",
			"Rene",
			"Descartes"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "pragmatism[10]  This author of The Principles of Psychology and \"The Will to Believe\" sought a middle ground between \"tough-minded\" and \"tender-minded\" philosophers in his work Pragmatism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 1 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this school of philosophy that emphasizes practical utility and uses actual value to define truth. It was espoused by John Dewey and the author of \"How to Make Our Ideas Clear\", C.S. Peirce (\"purse\").",
		"answers": [
			"pragmatism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"author",
			"The",
			"Principles",
			"Psychology",
			"and",
			"Will",
			"to",
			"Believe",
			"sought",
			"middle",
			"ground",
			"between",
			"tough-minded",
			"tender-minded",
			"philosophers",
			"in",
			"his",
			"work",
			"Pragmatism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "relativism[10]  This Greek sophist was an early relativist. His teachings are described in Theaetetus and his namesake Platonic dialogue, where he discussed if virtue can be taught. He famously stated \"man is the measure of all things\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 1 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This concept states that there is no absolute truth or validity, but that truth should be viewed within the reference frame of a language or culture. The \"moral\" type of this concept is particularly contentious.",
		"answers": [
			"relativism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Greek",
			"sophist",
			"was",
			"an",
			"early",
			"relativist",
			"His",
			"teachings",
			"are",
			"described",
			"in",
			"Theaetetus",
			"and",
			"his",
			"namesake",
			"Platonic",
			"dialogue",
			"where",
			"he",
			"discussed",
			"if",
			"virtue",
			"can",
			"be",
			"taught",
			"He",
			"famously",
			"stated",
			"man",
			"measure",
			"all",
			"things"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "separation of powers [prompt on \"tripartite system\"][10]  This French Enlightenment political philosopher articulated a theory of the separation of powers. He argued that monarchies relied on the principle of virtue, and despotisms relied on fear.",
		"prompts": [
			"tripartite",
			"system",
			"10",
			"This",
			"French",
			"Enlightenment",
			"political",
			"philosopher",
			"articulated",
			"theory",
			"separation",
			"powers",
			"He",
			"argued",
			"that",
			"monarchies",
			"relied",
			"principle",
			"virtue",
			"and",
			"despotisms",
			"relied",
			"fear"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 12 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This model proposes the division of the state into independent branches, each no more powerful than the others. This system often yields legislative, judicial, and executive branches.",
		"answers": [
			"separation",
			"powers"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Epicureanism[10]  This Roman Epicurean stated that the \"nature of mind and soul\" is \"corporeal\" in his De rerum natura, or \"On the Nature of Things\", which also asserts that nothing exists except bodies and the void.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 11 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical school, named after its Athenian founder, which believed pleasure to be the ultimate good, advocating moderate asceticism in order to be free from pain.",
		"answers": [
			"Epicureanism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Roman",
			"Epicurean",
			"stated",
			"that",
			"nature",
			"mind",
			"and",
			"soul",
			"corporeal",
			"in",
			"his",
			"De",
			"rerum",
			"natura",
			"On",
			"Nature",
			"Things",
			"which",
			"also",
			"asserts"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "\"On Denoting\"[10]  This writer of \"Why I am Not a Christian\" and \"On Denoting\" is also known for his namesake paradox, which pertains to a set of all sets that does not include itself.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 18 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this essay that attempts to tackle the problems of substitutivity, the excluded middle, and negative existentials by introducing a theory of definite descriptions.",
		"answers": [
			"On"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Summa Theologica [or Summation of Theology; prompt on \"Summa\"][10]  This Scholastic philosopher defended Christianity and put forth a four-part definition of faith in Summa con Gentiles, which he expanded on in Summa Theologica.",
		"prompts": [
			"Summa",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Scholastic",
			"philosopher",
			"defended",
			"Christianity",
			"and",
			"put",
			"forth",
			"four-part",
			"definition",
			"faith",
			"in",
			"Summa",
			"con",
			"Gentiles",
			"which",
			"he",
			"expanded",
			"in",
			"Summa",
			"Theologica"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round13.docx | 5 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this incomplete work structured as a series of objections and responses. It contains five arguments for the existence of God.",
		"answers": [
			"Summa",
			"Theologica",
			"Summation",
			"Theology"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "principle of sufficient reason[10]  This philosopher used the principle of sufficient reason to argue that the reason for this world is that it is the best of all possible worlds in Monadology.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 20 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this principle which states that all truths must have a cause.",
		"answers": [
			"principle",
			"sufficient",
			"reason",
			"10",
			"This",
			"philosopher",
			"used",
			"to",
			"argue",
			"that",
			"for",
			"this",
			"world",
			"best",
			"all",
			"possible",
			"worlds",
			"in",
			"Monadology"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Martin Heidegger[10]  This Heidegger work discusses viewing objects as a means to an end as being \"ready-to-hand\", as opposed to \"present-at-hand\". Heidegger never finished this work, so the part on the second title concept is incomplete.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 21 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this post-Kantian German philosopher, who argued that experience was grounded in intentionality and care. He coined the term Dasein to refer to a state of being that understands itself through its own existence.",
		"answers": [
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"10",
			"This",
			"work",
			"discusses",
			"viewing",
			"objects",
			"as",
			"means",
			"to",
			"an",
			"end",
			"being",
			"ready-to-hand",
			"opposed",
			"present-at-hand",
			"never",
			"finished",
			"this",
			"so",
			"part",
			"second",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"incomplete"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "arithmetic (or Arithmetik)[10]  This man had earlier analyzed the statement 7+5=12 in his Critique of Pure Reason. The most well-known formulation of his categorical imperative states that one should only do something if it should be done universally.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 18 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this discipline, the foundations of which were written about by Gottlob Frege. That work attacks the notion that 7+5=12 is a synthetic statement.",
		"answers": [
			"arithmetic",
			"Arithmetik",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"had",
			"earlier",
			"analyzed",
			"statement",
			"7+5=12",
			"in",
			"his",
			"Critique",
			"Pure",
			"Reason",
			"The",
			"most",
			"well-known",
			"formulation",
			"categorical",
			"imperative",
			"states",
			"that",
			"one",
			"should",
			"only",
			"something",
			"if",
			"be",
			"done",
			"universally"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Answer: Soren Kierkegaard (accept Anti-Climacus, John the Silent, or Johannes de Silentio)[10]  Some consider Kierkegaard to be the first philosopher from this movement, which claimed that the individual must be the starting point of philosophy. Other members of it included Simone de Beauvoir and Martin Heidegger.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round04.docx | 9 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Danish philosopher, author of The Sickness Unto Death and Fear and Trembling.",
		"answers": [
			"Answer:",
			"Soren",
			"Kierkegaard",
			"Anti-Climacus",
			"John",
			"Silent",
			"Johannes",
			"de",
			"Silentio",
			"10",
			"Some",
			"consider",
			"to",
			"be",
			"first",
			"philosopher",
			"from",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"which",
			"claimed",
			"that",
			"individual",
			"must",
			"starting",
			"point",
			"philosophy",
			"Other",
			"members",
			"included",
			"Simone",
			"Beauvoir",
			"and",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Rawls[10]  Rawls described this concept as a combination of liberty and equality in a work titled [this] as Fairness. His A Theory of [this] was refuted by Robert Nozick in Anarchy, State, and Utopia, and it's sometimes also defined as \"giving each his due\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 6 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this American philosopher whose \"original position\" parallels the \"state of nature\". He argued that inequalities in society should benefit the least advantaged, his \"difference principle\".",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Rawls",
			"10",
			"described",
			"this",
			"concept",
			"as",
			"combination",
			"liberty",
			"and",
			"equality",
			"in",
			"work",
			"titled",
			"Fairness",
			"His",
			"A",
			"Theory",
			"was",
			"refuted",
			"by",
			"Robert",
			"Nozick",
			"Anarchy",
			"State",
			"Utopia",
			"it's",
			"sometimes",
			"also",
			"defined",
			"giving",
			"each",
			"his",
			"due"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Being and Time (or Sein und Zeit)[10]  This German philosopher  joined the Nazi party soon after writing Being and Time. His other works include Kant and the Problem of Metaphysics and On the Way to Language.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical work, which uses phenomenological ontology to analyze the concept of Dasein, which describes the awareness of human consciousness.",
		"answers": [
			"Being",
			"and",
			"Time",
			"Sein",
			"und",
			"Zeit",
			"10",
			"This",
			"German",
			"philosopher",
			"joined",
			"Nazi",
			"party",
			"soon",
			"after",
			"writing",
			"His",
			"other",
			"works",
			"include",
			"Kant",
			"Problem",
			"Metaphysics",
			"On",
			"Way",
			"to",
			"Language"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus[10]  This Austrian philosopher wrote Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus and described the \"beetle in a box\" thought experiment in his posthumously published Philosophical Investigations.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 21 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical work comprised of seven propositions, such as \"the world is everything that is the case\" and \"whereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Tractatus",
			"Logico-Philosophicus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Austrian",
			"philosopher",
			"wrote",
			"and",
			"described",
			"beetle",
			"in",
			"box",
			"thought",
			"experiment",
			"his",
			"posthumously",
			"published",
			"Philosophical",
			"Investigations"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Stoicism (accept word forms)[10]  This founder of Stoicism rejected the cynicism of his teacher, Crates of Thebes. He declined Athenian citizenship in order to remain faithful to his native Citium.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 19 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Hellenistic school of philosophy which advocated for self-control to think clearly. Its members included Marcus Aurelius, Cicero, and Seneca the Younger.",
		"answers": [
			"Stoicism",
			"word",
			"forms",
			"10",
			"This",
			"founder",
			"rejected",
			"cynicism",
			"his",
			"teacher",
			"Crates",
			"Thebes",
			"He",
			"declined",
			"Athenian",
			"citizenship",
			"in",
			"order",
			"to",
			"remain",
			"faithful",
			"native",
			"Citium"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "John Stuart Mill[10]  Along with Jeremy Bentham, Mill is known as a proponent of this ethical theory, which maintains that the moral course of action is the one which results in the greatest good for the greatest number.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 5 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this English philosopher whose feminist ideas were published in \"The Subjection of Women\". He described his \"harm principle\" in On Liberty.",
		"answers": [
			"John",
			"Stuart",
			"Mill",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with",
			"Jeremy",
			"Bentham",
			"known",
			"as",
			"proponent",
			"this",
			"ethical",
			"theory",
			"which",
			"maintains",
			"that",
			"moral",
			"course",
			"action",
			"one",
			"results",
			"in",
			"greatest",
			"good",
			"for",
			"number"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "skepticism[10]  This Spanish-American philosopher discussed the title concept \"in religion\" and \"in common sense\" in The Sense of Beauty and wrote Scepticism and Animal Faith as well as The Life of Reason.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 4 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this philosophical school of thought which sought ataraxia, or \"freedom from worry\", and argued against absolute certainty in belief. One philosopher refuted it in a work titled [this] and Animal Faith.",
		"answers": [
			"skepticism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Spanish-American",
			"philosopher",
			"discussed",
			"title",
			"concept",
			"in",
			"religion",
			"and",
			"common",
			"sense",
			"The",
			"Sense",
			"Beauty",
			"wrote",
			"Scepticism",
			"Animal",
			"Faith",
			"as",
			"well",
			"Life",
			"Reason"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Leviathan[10]  This English philosopher and social contract theorist wrote that life in the state of nature was \"nasty, brutish, and short\" in  Leviathan. He also argued that an effective government must have absolute authority.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 22 | Philosophy |  | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this work which describes life without a central government as a \"war of all against all\". Its \"Of Man\" section describes the fear of violent death as the greatest evil.",
		"answers": [
			"Leviathan",
			"10",
			"This",
			"English",
			"philosopher",
			"and",
			"social",
			"contract",
			"theorist",
			"wrote",
			"that",
			"life",
			"in",
			"state",
			"nature",
			"was",
			"nasty",
			"brutish",
			"short",
			"He",
			"also",
			"argued",
			"an",
			"effective",
			"government",
			"must",
			"have",
			"absolute",
			"authority"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Immanuel Kant[10] Kant introduced this term that refers to the subjective experience of noumena. Kant claimed that knowledge was limited to these appearances of things, which are the only directly observable objects.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 6 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: He cited Horace's \"Sapere Aude\" as part of the transition out of immaturity in What is Enlightenment? For 10 points each:  [10] Name this philosopher who concluded that metaphysics is inherently dialectical in his Critique of Pure Reason. He also wrote the Critique of Judgment and the Metaphysics of Morals.",
		"answers": [
			"Immanuel",
			"Kant",
			"10",
			"introduced",
			"this",
			"term",
			"that",
			"refers",
			"to",
			"subjective",
			"experience",
			"noumena",
			"claimed",
			"knowledge",
			"was",
			"limited",
			"these",
			"appearances",
			"things",
			"which",
			"are",
			"only",
			"directly",
			"observable",
			"objects"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zeno[10] Another philosopher, Zeno of Citium, founded this school of philosophy, whose adherents included Epictetus and the Roman Emperor Marcus Aurelius. It proposed that virtue was the only good.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 19 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following questions about Classical philosophers, for 10 points each. [10] One philosopher of this name from Elea was a student of Parmenides, and according to a Platonic dialogue, debated a young Socrates. His paradoxes of motion feature the motionless arrow and Achilles racing a tortoise.",
		"answers": [
			"Zeno",
			"10"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "time[10] Martin Heidegger later joined the Nazis, whose central philosophy came from this anti-Semitic autobiography presaging Germany's invasion of Russia, written by an imprisoned Adolf Hitler.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 2 | Philosophy | None | HS",
		"subject": "Philosophy",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Immanuel Kant's transcendental aesthetic defines this as the a priori ability to perceive oneself, and Bergson contrasted this concept with \"free will.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this concept central to  a Martin Heidegger work that developed the concept of Dasein, in which it is contrasted with \"Being\".",
		"answers": [
			"time",
			"10",
			"Martin",
			"Heidegger",
			"later",
			"joined",
			"Nazis",
			"whose",
			"central",
			"philosophy",
			"came",
			"from",
			"this",
			"anti-Semitic",
			"autobiography",
			"presaging",
			"Germany's",
			"invasion",
			"Russia",
			"written",
			"by",
			"an",
			"imprisoned",
			"Adolf",
			"Hitler"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act [accept PPACA; accept Obamacare][10] Obamacare calls for the establishment of these health insurance markets. States have the option to create their own versions of these markets, partner with the federal government, or let the federal government establish one for them.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 5 | 7 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The majority of this law was upheld 5 to 4 in the case of National Federation of Independent Business v. Sebelius. For 10 points each: [10] Name this health care law which includes a contentious individual mandate and that is often informally referred to by the name of the president that signed it.",
		"answers": [
			"Patient",
			"Protection",
			"and",
			"Affordable",
			"Care",
			"Act",
			"PPACA",
			"Obamacare",
			"10",
			"calls",
			"for",
			"establishment",
			"these",
			"health",
			"insurance",
			"markets",
			"States",
			"have",
			"option",
			"to",
			"create",
			"their",
			"own",
			"versions",
			"partner",
			"with",
			"federal",
			"government",
			"let",
			"establish",
			"one",
			"them"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kate and William (accept Prince William, Duke of Cambridge and Catherine Middleton, Duchess of Cambridge; prompt on partial answer)[10] The Queen was the only female figure on English banknotes until the inclusion of this female novelist on the 10-pound note by new Governor of the Bank of England Mark Carney.",
		"prompts": [
			"partial",
			"answer",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Queen",
			"was",
			"only",
			"female",
			"figure",
			"English",
			"banknotes",
			"inclusion",
			"this",
			"female",
			"novelist",
			"10-pound",
			"note",
			"by",
			"new",
			"Governor",
			"Bank",
			"England",
			"Mark",
			"Carney"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 16 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: God save the Queen! For 10 points each: [10] On July 22, Queen Elizabeth II became a great-grandmother when this royal couple became the parents of Prince George Alexander Louis of Cambridge.",
		"answers": [
			"Kate",
			"and",
			"William",
			"Prince",
			"Duke",
			"Cambridge",
			"Catherine",
			"Middleton",
			"Duchess"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "George Walker Bush [accept Bush 43 or Bush the Younger; prompt on \"Bush\" or \"George Bush\"][10] This hispanic served as Bush's Attorney General. While serving in that position, this man dismissed many US Attorneys and used the NSA to wiretap U.S citizens without a warrant.",
		"prompts": [
			"Bush",
			"George",
			"Bush",
			"10",
			"This",
			"hispanic",
			"served",
			"as",
			"Bush's",
			"Attorney",
			"General",
			"While",
			"serving",
			"in",
			"that",
			"position",
			"this",
			"man",
			"dismissed",
			"many",
			"US",
			"Attorneys",
			"and",
			"used",
			"NSA",
			"to",
			"wiretap",
			"U",
			"S",
			"citizens",
			"without",
			"warrant"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 4 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Ann Richardson joked that this US politician was \"born with a silver foot in his mouth.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this former Texas governor. As president, he sent troops to Iraq to overthrow Saddam Hussein.",
		"answers": [
			"George",
			"Walker",
			"Bush",
			"43",
			"Younger"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "George Walker Bush [accept Bush 43 or Bush the Younger; prompt on \"Bush\" or \"George Bush\"][10] This hispanic served as Bush's Attorney General. While serving in that position, this man dismissed many US Attorneys and used the NSA to wiretap U.S citizens without a warrant.",
		"prompts": [
			"Bush",
			"George",
			"Bush",
			"10",
			"This",
			"hispanic",
			"served",
			"as",
			"Bush's",
			"Attorney",
			"General",
			"While",
			"serving",
			"in",
			"that",
			"position",
			"this",
			"man",
			"dismissed",
			"many",
			"US",
			"Attorneys",
			"and",
			"used",
			"NSA",
			"to",
			"wiretap",
			"U",
			"S",
			"citizens",
			"without",
			"warrant"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 8 | 4 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Ann Richardson joked that this US politician was \"born with a silver foot in his mouth.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this former Texas governor. As president, he sent troops to Iraq to overthrow Saddam Hussein.",
		"answers": [
			"George",
			"Walker",
			"Bush",
			"43",
			"Younger"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Trayvon Martin[10] This New York City policing policy of halting suspicious persons prompted arguments that it led to racial profiling. In August, a federal judge ruled it unconstitutional under the 4th Amendment.",
		"prompts": [
			"arguments",
			"that",
			"led",
			"to",
			"racial",
			"profiling",
			"In",
			"August",
			"federal",
			"judge",
			"ruled",
			"unconstitutional",
			"under",
			"4th",
			"Amendment"
		],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 17 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, answer some questions about current events that have involved race relations: [10] This Florida teenager's shooting by George Zimmerman sparked a nationwide debate and a contentious trial.",
		"answers": [
			"Trayvon",
			"Martin",
			"10",
			"This",
			"New",
			"York",
			"City",
			"policing",
			"policy",
			"halting",
			"suspicious",
			"persons"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "San Francisco[10] McDonald's still hasn't re-opened a franchise in this country, due to the low purchasing power of the krona. This nation is governed by the Althing.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 21 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] In 2010, led by Eric Mar, this California city banned the giving of toys along with Happy Meals. It later unrelatedly tried to ban circumcision, but the measure never made it onto the ballot.",
		"answers": [
			"San",
			"Francisco",
			"10",
			"McDonald's",
			"still",
			"hasn't",
			"re-opened",
			"franchise",
			"in",
			"this",
			"country",
			"due",
			"to",
			"low",
			"purchasing",
			"power",
			"krona",
			"This",
			"nation",
			"governed",
			"by",
			"Althing"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "minimum wage[10] A 2013 municipal referendum in this state set the minimum wage at its busiest airport to $15, the nation's  highest. In this state's largest city, socialist councilwoman Kshama Sawant supports raising the minimum wage",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 8 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This quantity is currently 7 dollars and 25 cents per hour nationally. For 10 points each: [10] Name this government-set lower bound on how much workers can be paid, last raised at the federal level in  2009.",
		"answers": [
			"minimum",
			"wage",
			"10",
			"A",
			"2013",
			"municipal",
			"referendum",
			"in",
			"this",
			"state",
			"set",
			"at",
			"its",
			"busiest",
			"airport",
			"to",
			"$15",
			"nation's",
			"highest",
			"In",
			"state's",
			"largest",
			"city",
			"socialist",
			"councilwoman",
			"Kshama",
			"Sawant",
			"supports",
			"raising"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "minimum wage[10] A 2013 municipal referendum in this state set the minimum wage at its busiest airport to $15, the nation's  highest. In this state's largest city, socialist councilwoman Kshama Sawant supports raising the minimum wage",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 8 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This quantity is currently 7 dollars and 25 cents per hour nationally. For 10 points each: [10] Name this government-set lower bound on how much workers can be paid, last raised at the federal level in  2009.",
		"answers": [
			"minimum",
			"wage",
			"10",
			"A",
			"2013",
			"municipal",
			"referendum",
			"in",
			"this",
			"state",
			"set",
			"at",
			"its",
			"busiest",
			"airport",
			"to",
			"$15",
			"nation's",
			"highest",
			"In",
			"state's",
			"largest",
			"city",
			"socialist",
			"councilwoman",
			"Kshama",
			"Sawant",
			"supports",
			"raising"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "News Corporation[10] One TV station owned by News Corporation is this conservative American station, designed to be a \"fourth  marketing force\" with CBS, ABC, and NBC. It is known for commentators like Bill O'Reilly and Glenn Beck.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 4 | 11 | Current Events | None | HS",
		"subject": "Current Events",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about corporate scandals, for 10 points each: [10] This corporation shut down its subsidiary the News of the World after that newspaper was found to have tapped  thousands of private telephone conversations.",
		"answers": [
			"News",
			"Corporation",
			"10",
			"One",
			"TV",
			"station",
			"owned",
			"by",
			"this",
			"conservative",
			"American",
			"designed",
			"to",
			"be",
			"fourth",
			"marketing",
			"force",
			"with",
			"CBS",
			"ABC",
			"and",
			"NBC",
			"It",
			"known",
			"for",
			"commentators",
			"Bill",
			"O'Reilly",
			"Glenn",
			"Beck"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Judges [or Sefer Shoftim][10] In the Book of Judges, this homicidal son of Gideon kills seventy of his brothers and meets his ignominious end when a lady fatally wounds him by tossing a mill-stone, prompting this man to instruct his armor-bearer to kill him so he wouldn't die at the hands of a woman.",
		"prompts": [
			"this",
			"man",
			"to",
			"instruct",
			"his",
			"armor-bearer",
			"to",
			"kill",
			"him",
			"so",
			"he",
			"wouldn't",
			"die",
			"at",
			"hands",
			"woman"
		],
		"heading": "PACE NSC |2015 | 4 | 18 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: In this book, Ehud tells the king Eglon \"I have a message from God for you,\" then stabs the overweight king in the abdomen so hard that his bowels leak out. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Biblical book in which Jephthah promises to sacrifice the first person he sees after a battle, who ends up being his own daughter, and Deborah teams up with Barak to defeat Sisera.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Judges",
			"Sefer",
			"Shoftim",
			"10",
			"In",
			"this",
			"homicidal",
			"son",
			"Gideon",
			"kills",
			"seventy",
			"his",
			"brothers",
			"and",
			"meets",
			"ignominious",
			"end",
			"when",
			"lady",
			"fatally",
			"wounds",
			"him",
			"by",
			"tossing",
			"mill-stone"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Simon Peter [prompt on \"Kephas\"][10] This Apostle is the only one not to have been martyred, but was exiled to the island of Patmos, where he had mystic visions and recorded them in the Book of Revelation.",
		"prompts": [
			"Kephas",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Apostle",
			"only",
			"one",
			"not",
			"to",
			"have",
			"been",
			"martyred",
			"but",
			"was",
			"exiled",
			"to",
			"island",
			"Patmos",
			"where",
			"he",
			"had",
			"mystic",
			"visions",
			"and",
			"recorded",
			"them",
			"in",
			"Book",
			"Revelation"
		],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 1 | 4 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name these Apostles of Jesus [10] This Apostle was crucified upside-down in Nero's Circus after seeing a vision of Jesus telling him to return to Rome. He is considered by Catholics to be the first Pope, and is buried underneath the altar of his namesake Basilica.",
		"answers": [
			"Simon",
			"Peter"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Hanukkah [or Chanukah; or Festival of Lights; or Feast of Dedication][10] This holiday is celebrated on the fourteenth day of Adar and commemorates an event in which Esther and Mordecai foiled Haman's plot to kill the Jews.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 2 | 15 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name the following Jewish holidays. [10] This eight-day holiday begins on the twenty-fifth day of Kislev and includes the lighting of the shamash on the nine-branched Menorah. It commemorates the reclaiming of the Temple in Jerusalem during the Maccabean Revolt.",
		"answers": [
			"Hanukkah",
			"Chanukah",
			"Festival",
			"Lights",
			"Feast",
			"Dedication",
			"10",
			"This",
			"holiday",
			"celebrated",
			"fourteenth",
			"day",
			"Adar",
			"and",
			"commemorates",
			"an",
			"event",
			"in",
			"which",
			"Esther",
			"Mordecai",
			"foiled",
			"Haman's",
			"plot",
			"to",
			"kill",
			"Jews"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Qur'an [or Koran][10] One source for interpretation of the Qur'an are these sayings and deeds of Muhammad. They are classified into the categories of authentic, good, and weak.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 3 | 20 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: With the exception of At-Tawba, each sura of this work begins with the basmala. [10] Name this holy text, said to have been dictated to Muhammad by the angel Jibril. It is the most important Islamic scripture.",
		"answers": [
			"Qur'an",
			"Koran",
			"10",
			"One",
			"source",
			"for",
			"interpretation",
			"are",
			"these",
			"sayings",
			"and",
			"deeds",
			"Muhammad",
			"They",
			"classified",
			"into",
			"categories",
			"authentic",
			"good",
			"weak"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Theravāda Buddhism [prompt on \"Hinayana Buddhism\"][10] Through the Sutta Pitaka, Theravada Buddhism teaches that there are four steps in achieving this state. One attempts to achieve this state to become an arahant, and the first stage in that process is being a \"stream-enterer.\"",
		"prompts": [
			"Hinayana",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"Through",
			"Sutta",
			"Pitaka",
			"Theravada",
			"Buddhism",
			"teaches",
			"that",
			"there",
			"are",
			"four",
			"steps",
			"in",
			"achieving",
			"this",
			"state",
			"One",
			"attempts",
			"to",
			"achieve",
			"this",
			"state",
			"to",
			"become",
			"an",
			"arahant",
			"and",
			"first",
			"stage",
			"in",
			"that",
			"process",
			"being",
			"stream-enterer"
		],
		"heading": "BELLOCO |2014 | 4 | 5 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This sect's standard collection of scriptures is the Pāli Canon. [10] Name this sect of Buddhism, which acknowledges only Gautama Buddha and teaches the incorruptibility of arahants. It is often contrasted with Mahayana Buddhism.",
		"answers": [
			"Theravāda",
			"Buddhism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Saint Stephen[10] This saint was beheaded under Diocletian for opposing his ban on Christian soldiers. He is the patron saint of England, and he is known for slaying a dragon in Cappadocia.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2014 | 2 | 12 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: One witness to this man's stoning was Saul of Tarsus, who held the coats of those who killed this man. For 10 points each: [10] Name this first martyr of Christianity, whose death is recorded in the Acts of the Apostles.",
		"answers": [
			"Saint",
			"Stephen",
			"10",
			"This",
			"saint",
			"was",
			"beheaded",
			"under",
			"Diocletian",
			"for",
			"opposing",
			"his",
			"ban",
			"Christian",
			"soldiers",
			"He",
			"patron",
			"England",
			"and",
			"he",
			"known",
			"slaying",
			"dragon",
			"in",
			"Cappadocia"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Beatitudes[10] The Sermon on the Mount is contained within Chapter 5 of this first book of the New Testament.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 2 | 5 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this collection of statements which claims that the kingdom of heaven awaits those poor in spirit and those who are persecuted for the sake of righteousness.",
		"answers": [
			"Beatitudes",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Sermon",
			"Mount",
			"contained",
			"within",
			"Chapter",
			"5",
			"this",
			"first",
			"book",
			"New",
			"Testament"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sabbath (accept Shabbath, Sabbatum, or Sabbaton)[10] Keeping the Sabbath day holy is required by the fourth of these laws. These also forbid killing and taking the Lord's name in vain.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Masonic |2014 | 2 | 6 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this day on which work was forbidden. In some traditions, travel outside the city walls was restricted to 2000 cubits, which is about half a mile.",
		"answers": [
			"Sabbath",
			"Shabbath",
			"Sabbatum",
			"Sabbaton",
			"10",
			"Keeping",
			"day",
			"holy",
			"required",
			"by",
			"fourth",
			"these",
			"laws",
			"These",
			"also",
			"forbid",
			"killing",
			"and",
			"taking",
			"Lord's",
			"name",
			"in",
			"vain"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zen Buddhism [10] Zen Buddhism supposedly had its legend in this story in which Buddha handed the namesake object to his follower Mahakashyapa while sitting at a pond.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "NASAT  |2014 | 20 | 4 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The Sanskrit word \"Dhyana\" is the origin for the name of this religion. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this branch of Mahayana Buddhism that asks unanswerable questions called koans and is practiced in Eastern Asia. ",
		"answers": [
			"Zen",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"supposedly",
			"had",
			"its",
			"legend",
			"in",
			"this",
			"story",
			"which",
			"Buddha",
			"handed",
			"namesake",
			"object",
			"to",
			"his",
			"follower",
			"Mahakashyapa",
			"while",
			"sitting",
			"at",
			"pond"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "hajj[10] This other pillar of Islam involves giving alms to the poor and needy. Its non-Muslim equivalent is the Jizyah tax.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 01 | 8 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: For 10 points each, name some things associated with pillars of Islam. [10] This pillar of Islam, which takes place during the last month of the Islamic calendar, is a ritual pilgrimage to Mecca.",
		"answers": [
			"hajj",
			"10",
			"This",
			"other",
			"pillar",
			"Islam",
			"involves",
			"giving",
			"alms",
			"to",
			"poor",
			"and",
			"needy",
			"Its",
			"non-Muslim",
			"equivalent",
			"Jizyah",
			"tax"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gematriya[10] This is the number of days of Creation in Genesis including resting, the number of holy virtues and deadly sins in Christianity, and the number of skies or heavens in a variety of religions including Islam.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 02 | 6 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer the following about significant numbers in religion, for 10 points each. [10] This Jewish numerological tradition assigns numbers to letters, words, and phrases. In this system, the letters of chai, meaning life, add to 18, which is therefore considered a lucky number.",
		"answers": [
			"gematriya",
			"10",
			"This",
			"number",
			"days",
			"Creation",
			"in",
			"Genesis",
			"including",
			"resting",
			"holy",
			"virtues",
			"and",
			"deadly",
			"sins",
			"Christianity",
			"skies",
			"heavens",
			"variety",
			"religions",
			"Islam"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Kaddish[10] This prayer, traditionally said twice a day, is a restatement of three passages from the Bible, starting with \"Hear O Israel, the LORD is God, the LORD is one.\" Along with the Amidah, it is one of the central prayers in Judaism.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 03 | 18 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about bits of the Jewish prayer service for 10 points each. [10] This prayer, one kind of which is said by mourners, is used to split up sections of a prayer service. It needs 10 Jewish adults present to be said.",
		"answers": [
			"Kaddish",
			"10",
			"This",
			"prayer",
			"traditionally",
			"said",
			"twice",
			"day",
			"restatement",
			"three",
			"passages",
			"from",
			"Bible",
			"starting",
			"with",
			"Hear",
			"O",
			"Israel",
			"LORD",
			"God",
			"one",
			"Along",
			"Amidah",
			"central",
			"prayers",
			"in",
			"Judaism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Quakers [accept Religious Society of Friends][10] This man founded the Quakers. He was arrested for blasphemy twice, once while preaching under a tree at Balby.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 05 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Followers of this religion were known for their opposition to slavery. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Christian sect known for its pacifism. Its colloquial name comes from the command to \"tremble at the word of the Lord.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Quakers",
			"Religious",
			"Society",
			"Friends",
			"10",
			"This",
			"man",
			"founded",
			"He",
			"was",
			"arrested",
			"for",
			"blasphemy",
			"twice",
			"once",
			"while",
			"preaching",
			"under",
			"tree",
			"at",
			"Balby"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Esther [or Hadassah][10] This woman set the precedent for conversion and familial piety in her namesake book by telling her mother-in-law that \"your people shall be my people, and your God shall be my God\".",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 06 | 5 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about women who have their own Old Testament books, for 10 points each. [10] This woman married the Persian king in order to stop a plot to kill the Jews. Her namesake book forms the basis for the holiday Purim.",
		"answers": [
			"Esther",
			"Hadassah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"woman",
			"set",
			"precedent",
			"for",
			"conversion",
			"and",
			"familial",
			"piety",
			"in",
			"her",
			"namesake",
			"book",
			"by",
			"telling",
			"mother-in-law",
			"that",
			"your",
			"people",
			"shall",
			"be",
			"my",
			"God"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Australia[10] The Tjurunga cannot be approached by people who have not undergone this rite. Women, foreigners, and children who have not come of age cannot undergo this.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2014 | 07 | 17 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer these questions about totems called Tjurungu (\"chuh-ROON-guh\"), for 10 points each: [10] Tjurunga are spiritual totems of indigenous people from this country. Those people are collectively known as \"Aborigines.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Australia",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Tjurunga"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Haile Selassie I [accept Tafari Makonnen Woldimikael][10] Adherents of this movement believe Haile Selassie to be the messiah. Practices in this faith include the dietary law of ital and the religious use of cannabis.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 1 | 16 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man's arrival in Jamaica is celebrated as Grounation Day. For 10 points each: [10] Name this final Ethiopian emperor, whom a certain faith believes to be the incarnate of the Jah and will lead the righteous to create Zion.",
		"answers": [
			"Haile",
			"Selassie",
			"I",
			"Tafari",
			"Makonnen",
			"Woldimikael",
			"10",
			"Adherents",
			"this",
			"movement",
			"believe",
			"to",
			"be",
			"messiah",
			"Practices",
			"in",
			"faith",
			"include",
			"dietary",
			"law",
			"ital",
			"and",
			"religious",
			"use",
			"cannabis"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "the Bahá'í Faith [accept Bahá'íyyah][10] The Bahá'í Faith was founded by Bahá'u'lláh, who had been a follower of this mystic who claimed to be the Mahdi of Islam. He was executed by firing squad for apostasy.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 4 | 20 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This religion's founder described his journey to enlightenment in The Seven Valleys. For 10 points each: [10] Name this monotheistic religion which claims that most major religions have been inspired by the same God.",
		"answers": [
			"the",
			"Bahá'í",
			"Faith",
			"Bahá'íyyah",
			"10",
			"The",
			"was",
			"founded",
			"by",
			"Bahá'u'lláh",
			"who",
			"had",
			"been",
			"follower",
			"this",
			"mystic",
			"claimed",
			"to",
			"be",
			"Mahdi",
			"Islam",
			"He",
			"executed",
			"firing",
			"squad",
			"for",
			"apostasy"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Samsara[10] This concept refers to liberation from the cycle of Samsara; in Hinduism, this concept allows one to leave behind mundane things and rejoin with Brahman.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 5 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Buddhism, Hinduism, and Jainism share similar concepts of enlightenment. For 10 points each: [10] Name this endless cycle of birth, death, and rebirth that translates from Sanskrit as \"Journeying.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Samsara",
			"10",
			"This",
			"concept",
			"refers",
			"to",
			"liberation",
			"from",
			"cycle",
			"in",
			"Hinduism",
			"this",
			"allows",
			"one",
			"leave",
			"behind",
			"mundane",
			"things",
			"and",
			"rejoin",
			"with",
			"Brahman"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shabbat [or Shabbos][10] Shabbat is commenced using two of these objects, over which the head female of the household typically says a blessing.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 6 | 17 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: It is said that manna did not fall on this day, and people who observe this day are prohibited from building, writing, or transporting property across boundaries. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Jewish day of rest, which falls on the seventh of every week.",
		"answers": [
			"Shabbat",
			"Shabbos",
			"10",
			"commenced",
			"using",
			"two",
			"these",
			"objects",
			"over",
			"which",
			"head",
			"female",
			"household",
			"typically",
			"says",
			"blessing"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Voodoo [accept Vodun][10] These spirits in Voodoo have no creative power like Bondye, but their nanchons rule every physical and social realm. They include figures like Marinette, Agwé, and Baron Samedi.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "GSAC |2013 | 7 | 6 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Religious figures in this religion are called houngan and mambo, if male or female respectively. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Haitian religion that syncretized West African and Catholic beliefs, famous for its namesake \"dolls.\"",
		"answers": [
			"Voodoo",
			"Vodun",
			"10",
			"These",
			"spirits",
			"in",
			"have",
			"no",
			"creative",
			"power",
			"Bondye",
			"but",
			"their",
			"nanchons",
			"rule",
			"every",
			"physical",
			"and",
			"social",
			"realm",
			"They",
			"include",
			"figures",
			"Marinette",
			"Agwé",
			"Baron",
			"Samedi"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zen or Ch'an Buddhism[10] Koans in this 13th century collection published by the monk Wumen include the stories of Gutei's finger and the lack of Bodhidharma's beard. It is often cited with the Blue Cliff Record as a major source of koans.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 11 | 20 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Koans from the Rinzai sect of this religion include \"does a dog have the Buddha's nature\", and \"what was your face before your parents were born?\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this primarily Japanese sect of Buddhism which emphasizes the use of koans to achieve enlightenment. Enlightenment may also be achieved through strict meditation.",
		"answers": [
			"Zen",
			"Ch'an",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"Koans",
			"in",
			"this",
			"13th",
			"century",
			"collection",
			"published",
			"by",
			"monk",
			"Wumen",
			"include",
			"stories",
			"Gutei's",
			"finger",
			"and",
			"lack",
			"Bodhidharma's",
			"beard",
			"It",
			"often",
			"cited",
			"with",
			"Blue",
			"Cliff",
			"Record",
			"as",
			"major",
			"source",
			"koans"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Vodou (pronounced \"Voodoo\"; accept Vodun) [10] These spirits are venerated in Vodou. They are represented by vÃ©vÃ© symbols, which act as beacons to them.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 13 | 2 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Priestesses in this religion are called mambo and priests are called houngan. For 10 points each:  [10] Name this religion based in Haiti with African and Catholic elements. It is associated by many people with the sticking of pins into dolls to curse people.",
		"answers": [
			"Vodou",
			"pronounced",
			"Voodoo",
			"Vodun",
			"10",
			"These",
			"spirits",
			"are",
			"venerated",
			"in",
			"They",
			"represented",
			"by",
			"vÃ©vÃ©",
			"symbols",
			"which",
			"act",
			"as",
			"beacons",
			"to",
			"them"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Abraham or Abram[10] Sarah asked Abraham to cast out this handmaid following the birth of Isaac. She was the mother of Abraham's firstborn son, Ishmael.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 2 | 8 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This man was told that his descendants would be \"as numerous as the stars in the sky.\" For 10 points each: [10] Name this patriarch of some namesake monotheistic religions who once claimed that his wife, Sarah, was actually his sister. He also nearly sacrificed their only son, Isaac, to God.",
		"answers": [
			"Abraham",
			"Abram",
			"10",
			"Sarah",
			"asked",
			"to",
			"cast",
			"out",
			"this",
			"handmaid",
			"following",
			"birth",
			"Isaac",
			"She",
			"was",
			"mother",
			"Abraham's",
			"firstborn",
			"son",
			"Ishmael"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Dead Sea Scrolls[10] This manuscript was the first comprehensive translation of the Bible into Latin from Hebrew, and was made by St. Jerome. It replaced the Vetus Latina.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 5 | 11 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: There are many manuscripts associated with parts of the Bible. For 10 points each:  [10] These Hebrew manuscripts were found on the shore of a body of water near the present-day West Bank, and are named for that location. ",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Dead",
			"Sea",
			"Scrolls",
			"10",
			"This",
			"manuscript",
			"was",
			"first",
			"comprehensive",
			"translation",
			"Bible",
			"into",
			"Latin",
			"from",
			"Hebrew",
			"and",
			"made",
			"by",
			"St",
			"Jerome",
			"It",
			"replaced",
			"Vetus",
			"Latina"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "gurus[10] Gurus are from this religion which originated in Punjab in the 15th Century. Most male followers wear turbans and are prohibited from cutting their hair.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 7 | 10 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: The last and eternal one of these figures is a book written entirely in song, the Adi Granth. For 10 points each: [10] Name this group of ten religious figures which began with Nanak Dev.",
		"answers": [
			"gurus",
			"10",
			"Gurus",
			"are",
			"from",
			"this",
			"religion",
			"which",
			"originated",
			"in",
			"Punjab",
			"15th",
			"Century",
			"Most",
			"male",
			"followers",
			"wear",
			"turbans",
			"and",
			"prohibited",
			"cutting",
			"their",
			"hair"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lent[10] In the Catholic church and many other denominations, Lent ends on this day. This day commemorates the Last Supper, and priests traditionally wash the feet of their parishioners on this day.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "James |2013 | 9 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: It commemorates the 40 days that Jesus fasted in the desert and was tempted by the Devil. For 10 points each: [10] ] Name this period of the Christian calendar that starts on Ash Wednesday and lasts for forty days. Christians often \"give up\" something during this time.",
		"answers": [
			"Lent",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Catholic",
			"church",
			"and",
			"many",
			"other",
			"denominations",
			"ends",
			"this",
			"day",
			"This",
			"commemorates",
			"Last",
			"Supper",
			"priests",
			"traditionally",
			"wash",
			"feet",
			"their",
			"parishioners"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nation of Islam (accept NOI; do not accept or prompt on \"Islam\")[10] The Nation of Islam differs from conventional Islam in believing that there was an additional messenger of Allah after this man, who is ordinarily considered the final prophet. The angel Gabriel dictated the Qur'an to this man.",
		"prompts": [
			"Islam",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"differs",
			"from",
			"conventional",
			"Islam",
			"in",
			"believing",
			"that",
			"there",
			"was",
			"an",
			"additional",
			"messenger",
			"Allah",
			"after",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"ordinarily",
			"considered",
			"final",
			"prophet",
			"The",
			"angel",
			"Gabriel",
			"dictated",
			"Qur'an",
			"to",
			"this",
			"man"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2013 | 1 | 7 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10] Name this predominantly African-American faith founded by Wallace D. Fard. It is presently led by Louis Farrakhan, and Malcolm X was once an adherent of it.",
		"answers": [
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"NOI"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "People of the Book [or Ahl-al-Kitab; or dhimmi; or zimm][10] Zakat, the pillar of Islam mandating this activity, is replaced for People of the Book by the jizya tax. The standard amount for the zakat type of it is 2.5 percent of one's income.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "PACE |2013 | 3 | 7 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: All definitions of this concept exclude Baha'i, since that faith emerged after Muhammad, and Persian dynasties varied on whether Zoroastrians count as this type of person. For 10 points each: [10] Name this class in Islamic society, the set of non-Muslims who, in contrast to infidels, retained some freedoms because they also believe in the Abrahamic god.",
		"answers": [
			"People",
			"Book",
			"Ahl-al-Kitab",
			"dhimmi",
			"zimm",
			"10",
			"Zakat",
			"pillar",
			"Islam",
			"mandating",
			"this",
			"activity",
			"replaced",
			"for",
			"by",
			"jizya",
			"tax",
			"The",
			"standard",
			"amount",
			"zakat",
			"type",
			"2",
			"5",
			"percent",
			"one's",
			"income"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Jainism[10]  This cycle of life, death, and reincarnation is a central concept in Indian religions such as Jainism, Buddhism, and Hinduism. It is ended by moksha.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round02.docx | 14 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Indian religion emphasizing a strict view of ahimsa, or non-violence. Monks of this religion observe five vows or the Mahavrata, including ahimsa, satya, and aparigraha.",
		"answers": [
			"Jainism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"cycle",
			"life",
			"death",
			"and",
			"reincarnation",
			"central",
			"concept",
			"in",
			"Indian",
			"religions",
			"such",
			"as",
			"Buddhism",
			"Hinduism",
			"It",
			"ended",
			"by",
			"moksha"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "turban [accept pagri, bulle, or dastar][10]  Worn by Muslim women, it is a full-body covering meant to fulfill the requirements of hijab. Some say that the veil portion of this garment is unnecessary in the presence of blind or gay men.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round03.docx | 20 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This head covering is worn by Sikh men, in part to cover their uncut hair. In Kenya, the Akurinu wear these, and pink ones are worn in India for marriage ceremonies.",
		"answers": [
			"turban",
			"pagri",
			"bulle",
			"dastar",
			"10",
			"Worn",
			"by",
			"Muslim",
			"women",
			"full-body",
			"covering",
			"meant",
			"to",
			"fulfill",
			"requirements",
			"hijab",
			"Some",
			"say",
			"that",
			"veil",
			"portion",
			"this",
			"garment",
			"unnecessary",
			"in",
			"presence",
			"blind",
			"gay",
			"men"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gabriel[10]  This archangel and Gabriel are the only ones mentioned in the Qur'an. He is the patron saint of the military, police force, paramedics, and the city of Brussels. He leads God's army into battle against Satan in the Book of Revelation.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round04.docx | 17 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This angel revealed the Qur'an to Muhammad over twenty-three years. In Mormonism, he and Noah are the same being. He is known for foretelling the birth of John the Baptist and Jesus Christ.",
		"answers": [
			"Gabriel",
			"10",
			"This",
			"archangel",
			"and",
			"are",
			"only",
			"ones",
			"in",
			"Qur'an",
			"He",
			"patron",
			"saint",
			"military",
			"police",
			"force",
			"paramedics",
			"city",
			"Brussels",
			"leads",
			"God's",
			"army",
			"into",
			"battle",
			"against",
			"Satan",
			"Book",
			"Revelation"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gnosticism[10]  One prominent symbol of Gnosticism is the \"sun\" type of this symbol. A \"Greek\" type of this symbol has four equal-length arms and symbolizes the Eastern Orthodox church.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round06.docx | 18 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this movement which believes in Sophia, an embodiment of wisdom who births an imperfect demiurge which then creates the universe. This religion derives its name from the Greek word for \"knowledge\".",
		"answers": [
			"Gnosticism",
			"10",
			"One",
			"prominent",
			"symbol",
			"sun",
			"type",
			"this",
			"A",
			"Greek",
			"has",
			"four",
			"equal-length",
			"arms",
			"and",
			"symbolizes",
			"Eastern",
			"Orthodox",
			"church"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Baha'i[10]  This is the primary text of the Baha'i faith. It includes a passage known as the \"Tablet of the True Seeker,\" and is also known as the Book of Iqan.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round07.docx | 6 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this religion that teaches of divine messengers including Moses, the Buddha, and Mohammed, the most recent ones being the Bab and Baha'u'llah.",
		"answers": [
			"Baha'i",
			"10",
			"This",
			"primary",
			"text",
			"faith",
			"It",
			"includes",
			"passage",
			"known",
			"as",
			"Tablet",
			"True",
			"Seeker",
			"and",
			"also",
			"Book",
			"Iqan"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Palm Sunday [accept Passion Sunday][10]  This was final meal Jesus had with his apostles. Jesus foresaw a betrayal from one of his disciples, washed their feet, and predicted that St. Peter would deny knowing him at this event.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round08.docx | 6 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Commemorating Jesus' entry into Jerusalem, riding a donkey while others shouted \"Hosanna!,\" it is celebrated by the distribution of its namesake branches to celebrators, although yew or willow are also used.",
		"answers": [
			"Palm",
			"Sunday",
			"Passion",
			"10",
			"This",
			"was",
			"final",
			"meal",
			"Jesus",
			"had",
			"with",
			"his",
			"apostles",
			"foresaw",
			"betrayal",
			"from",
			"one",
			"disciples",
			"washed",
			"their",
			"feet",
			"and",
			"predicted",
			"that",
			"St",
			"Peter",
			"would",
			"deny",
			"knowing",
			"him",
			"at",
			"this",
			"event"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Lent [accept Quadragesima][10]  This month of fasting precedes Shawaal. Laylat al-Qadr occurred during this month, during which meals called suhoor and iftar are eaten before dawn and at sunset, respectively.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round10.docx | 20 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Abstinence from animal products was formerly daily during these forty days, but in modern times is generally observed on Fridays. Ash Wednesday, a day of fasting, marks the beginning of this holiday that ends before Easter.",
		"answers": [
			"Lent",
			"Quadragesima",
			"10",
			"This",
			"month",
			"fasting",
			"precedes",
			"Shawaal",
			"Laylat",
			"al-Qadr",
			"occurred",
			"during",
			"this",
			"which",
			"meals",
			"called",
			"suhoor",
			"and",
			"iftar",
			"are",
			"eaten",
			"dawn",
			"at",
			"sunset",
			"respectively"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Zoroastrianism [prompt on \"Mazdaism\" or \"Magianism\"][10]  This is the primary sacred text of Zoroastrianism, containing the Yasnas and the Gathas.",
		"prompts": [
			"Mazdaism",
			"Magianism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"primary",
			"sacred",
			"text",
			"Zoroastrianism",
			"containing",
			"Yasnas",
			"and",
			"Gathas"
		],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round11.docx | 8 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this religion teaching that Ahura Mazda will eventually prevail over the evil Angra Mainyu, whose practitioners may expose corpses on a Tower of Silence before cremating them.",
		"answers": [
			"Zoroastrianism"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "voodoo [accept vodoun or vodon][10]  In voodoo, these beings are emissaries of Bondye, as he is too great to directly intervene in human lives. Nanchons of these include Ghede, Petro, Kongo, and Rada.  People \"mounted\" or possessed by these are called \"horses.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round12.docx | 11 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This syncretic chief religion of Haiti believes in a supreme god called Bondye. A temple in this religion is called a Hounfour, and female priests are called Mambos.",
		"answers": [
			"voodoo",
			"vodoun",
			"vodon",
			"10",
			"In",
			"these",
			"beings",
			"are",
			"emissaries",
			"Bondye",
			"as",
			"he",
			"too",
			"great",
			"to",
			"directly",
			"intervene",
			"in",
			"human",
			"lives",
			"Nanchons",
			"include",
			"Ghede",
			"Petro",
			"Kongo",
			"and",
			"Rada",
			"People",
			"mounted",
			"possessed",
			"by",
			"called",
			"horses"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shia Islam [or Shi'ites][10]  This sect of Shia Islam is represented by a five-point star, and is centered in Lebanon and Syria. They are divided into the uqqal and the jahhal. Unlike other sects, adherents are not required to observe most religious rituals.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round14.docx | 5 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This second largest branch of Islam believes that Muhammad's successor was his son-in-law, the first imam. The Alavis, Ismaili, and Zaidi are part of this branch.",
		"answers": [
			"Shia",
			"Islam",
			"Shi'ites",
			"10",
			"This",
			"sect",
			"represented",
			"by",
			"five-point",
			"star",
			"and",
			"centered",
			"in",
			"Lebanon",
			"Syria",
			"They",
			"are",
			"divided",
			"into",
			"uqqal",
			"jahhal",
			"Unlike",
			"other",
			"sects",
			"adherents"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "circumcision[10]  This is the Jewish term for ritual circumcision, in which the kvatter carries the baby from the parents to the mohel. After this ceremony, participants are compelled to attend a seudat mitzvah.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2013 | Round15.docx | 17 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this surgical action which Jesus underwent when he was 8 days old, which resulted in the Holy Prepuce. Some Indigenous Australians have this procedure as well as subincision as part of rites of passage.",
		"answers": [
			"circumcision",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Jewish",
			"term",
			"for",
			"ritual",
			"in",
			"which",
			"kvatter",
			"carries",
			"baby",
			"from",
			"parents",
			"to",
			"mohel",
			"After",
			"this",
			"ceremony",
			"participants",
			"are",
			"compelled",
			"attend",
			"seudat",
			"mitzvah"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Nation of Islam (accept NOI; do not accept or prompt on \"Islam\")[10]  The Nation of Islam differs from conventional Islam in believing that there was an additional messenger of Allah after this man, who is ordinarily considered the final prophet. The angel Gabriel dictated the Qur'an to this man.",
		"prompts": [
			"Islam",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"differs",
			"from",
			"conventional",
			"Islam",
			"in",
			"believing",
			"that",
			"there",
			"was",
			"an",
			"additional",
			"messenger",
			"Allah",
			"after",
			"this",
			"man",
			"who",
			"ordinarily",
			"considered",
			"final",
			"prophet",
			"The",
			"angel",
			"Gabriel",
			"dictated",
			"Qur'an",
			"to",
			"this",
			"man"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round01.docx | 7 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this predominantly African-American faith founded by Wallace D. Fard. It is presently led by Louis Farrakhan, and Malcolm X was once an adherent of it.",
		"answers": [
			"Nation",
			"Islam",
			"NOI"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sermon on the Mount (or Sermo in Monte)[10]  The Sermon on the Mount is found in this first of the four Gospels. Its presumed author was a tax collector from Capernaum.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round02.docx | 2 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this collection of teachings given by Jesus from a large hill, which also contains the Beatitudes.",
		"answers": [
			"Sermon",
			"Mount",
			"Sermo",
			"in",
			"Monte",
			"10",
			"The",
			"found",
			"this",
			"first",
			"four",
			"Gospels",
			"Its",
			"presumed",
			"author",
			"was",
			"tax",
			"collector",
			"from",
			"Capernaum"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "New Years (accept obvious equivalents)[10]  Like at Yom Kippur, services at Rosh Hashanah often include the blowing of this ram's horn.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round03.docx | 5 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Rosh Hashanah is a holiday celebrating one of these annual occurrences, which occurs on January 1 in the Gregorian calendar. The Chinese celebrate a \"Lunar\" one of these in February.",
		"answers": [
			"New",
			"Years",
			"obvious",
			"equivalents",
			"10",
			"Like",
			"at",
			"Yom",
			"Kippur",
			"services",
			"Rosh",
			"Hashanah",
			"often",
			"include",
			"blowing",
			"this",
			"ram's",
			"horn"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "kirpan[10]  The kirpan is one of the Five Ks of this religion, whose male members are required to wear turbans. This religion follows the teachings of eleven gurus, including its founder, Guru Nanak.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round05.docx | 4 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this religiously symbolic dagger which is used to stir a sugar and water mixture during the baptism ceremony of a certain religion.",
		"answers": [
			"kirpan",
			"10",
			"The",
			"one",
			"Five",
			"Ks",
			"this",
			"religion",
			"whose",
			"male",
			"members",
			"are",
			"required",
			"to",
			"wear",
			"turbans",
			"This",
			"follows",
			"teachings",
			"eleven",
			"gurus",
			"including",
			"its",
			"founder",
			"Guru",
			"Nanak"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "seder[10]  The seder is a meal during this holiday, which celebrates the exodus of Jews from slavery in Egypt.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round06.docx | 11 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this festive event occurring on the 14th of Nisan, which marks the beginning of a certain weeklong holiday. During it, the youngest child asks the Four Questions, and it includes the hiding of the matzah afikomen.",
		"answers": [
			"seder",
			"10",
			"The",
			"meal",
			"during",
			"this",
			"holiday",
			"which",
			"celebrates",
			"exodus",
			"Jews",
			"from",
			"slavery",
			"in",
			"Egypt"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "names of God (accept answers specifying a Jewish God or Islamic God; prompt on \"names of Allah\")[10]  This mystical sect of Islam highly encourages dhikr and other forms of devotion to Allah. This group's dervishes also engage in a notable \"whirling\" dance.",
		"prompts": [
			"names",
			"Allah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"mystical",
			"sect",
			"Islam",
			"highly",
			"encourages",
			"dhikr",
			"and",
			"other",
			"forms",
			"devotion",
			"to",
			"Allah",
			"This",
			"group's",
			"dervishes",
			"also",
			"engage",
			"in",
			"notable",
			"whirling",
			"dance"
		],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round07.docx | 13 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify these types of words, other examples of which include the Tetragrammaton YHWH (\"yah-weh\") and Adonai.",
		"answers": [
			"names",
			"God",
			"specifying",
			"Jewish",
			"Islamic"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Mahayana Buddhism[10]  This highest-ranking lama leads the Yellow-hat Buddhists. The current holder of this position is Tenzin Gyatso, who used to lead the Tibetan government-in-exile.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round08.docx | 15 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Tibetan Buddhism is an offshoot of this \"Great Vehicle\" branch of Buddhism, which is often contrasted with the Theravada school.",
		"answers": [
			"Mahayana",
			"Buddhism",
			"10",
			"This",
			"highest-ranking",
			"lama",
			"leads",
			"Yellow-hat",
			"Buddhists",
			"The",
			"current",
			"holder",
			"this",
			"position",
			"Tenzin",
			"Gyatso",
			"who",
			"used",
			"to",
			"lead",
			"Tibetan",
			"government-in-exile"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Purim[10]  This wintertime Jewish \"festival of lights\" begins on the 25th of Kislev and commemorates the Maccabees' defeat of Antiochus and the re-dedication of the Temple. It sees the lighting of a nine-branched menorah.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round09.docx | 10 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  This holiday celebrates the foiling of the evil Haman's plot by Esther and Mordechai.",
		"answers": [
			"Purim",
			"10",
			"This",
			"wintertime",
			"Jewish",
			"festival",
			"lights",
			"begins",
			"25th",
			"Kislev",
			"and",
			"commemorates",
			"Maccabees'",
			"defeat",
			"Antiochus",
			"re-dedication",
			"Temple",
			"It",
			"sees",
			"lighting",
			"nine-branched",
			"menorah"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "The Lord's Prayer  (accept Our Father or Pater Noster)[10]  The Lord's prayer is often said before this sacrament, whose participants take bread and wine that, according to the Catholic and Orthodox churches, have been transubstantiated into the body and blood of Christ.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round10.docx | 19 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Name this Christian prayer which asks the title figure to \"forgive us our trespasses\" and to \"lead us not to temptation, but deliver us from evil\".",
		"answers": [
			"The",
			"Lord's",
			"Prayer",
			"Our",
			"Father",
			"Pater",
			"Noster",
			"10",
			"prayer",
			"often",
			"said",
			"this",
			"sacrament",
			"whose",
			"participants",
			"take",
			"bread",
			"and",
			"wine",
			"that",
			"according",
			"to",
			"Catholic",
			"Orthodox",
			"churches",
			"have",
			"been",
			"transubstantiated",
			"into",
			"body",
			"blood",
			"Christ"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Ramadan[10]  The practice of fasting is referred to by this Arabic word, one of the Five Pillars of Islam. It refers to total abstinence from things such as food, drinking, marital relations, and swearing during the day.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 7 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this month of the Islamic calendar, during which able-bodied Muslims fast from dawn to dusk.",
		"answers": [
			"Ramadan",
			"10",
			"The",
			"practice",
			"fasting",
			"referred",
			"to",
			"by",
			"this",
			"Arabic",
			"word",
			"one",
			"Five",
			"Pillars",
			"Islam",
			"It",
			"refers",
			"total",
			"abstinence",
			"from",
			"things",
			"such",
			"as",
			"food",
			"drinking",
			"marital",
			"relations",
			"and",
			"swearing",
			"during",
			"day"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "battle tanks[10]  The tanks central to the Nazi technique of Blitzkrieg during World War II were typically referred to by this name, the German word for \"armor.\"",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round11.docx | 18 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify these armored battle vehicles which typically have a turreted main gun and move around on treads. They were first used in World War I at the Battle of the Somme.",
		"answers": [
			"battle",
			"tanks",
			"10",
			"The",
			"central",
			"to",
			"Nazi",
			"technique",
			"Blitzkrieg",
			"during",
			"World",
			"War",
			"II",
			"were",
			"typically",
			"referred",
			"by",
			"this",
			"name",
			"German",
			"word",
			"for",
			"armor"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Laozi or Lao-Tsu[10]  Laozi was the founder of this Asian religion, the symbol of which is the black and white circle of yin and yang, and whose text is the Tao Te Ching.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round12.docx | 16 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this sixth century BC figure, whom Tang emperors claimed descent from. This founder of a certain religion is believed to be one of the Three Pure Ones, and he supposedly lived in his mother's womb for 70 years.",
		"answers": [
			"Laozi",
			"Lao-Tsu",
			"10",
			"was",
			"founder",
			"this",
			"Asian",
			"religion",
			"symbol",
			"which",
			"black",
			"and",
			"white",
			"circle",
			"yin",
			"yang",
			"whose",
			"text",
			"Tao",
			"Te",
			"Ching"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Druze[10]  The Druze have flag and star have this many points and colors. This is the number of Pillars of Islam and books in the Torah.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round13.docx | 8 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this primarily Middle Eastern faith, whose seven pillars include telling the truth and protecting one's fellow adherents. It evolved from Ismailism, and is predominantly practiced in Syria and Lebanon.",
		"answers": [
			"Druze",
			"10",
			"The",
			"have",
			"flag",
			"and",
			"star",
			"this",
			"many",
			"points",
			"colors",
			"This",
			"number",
			"Pillars",
			"Islam",
			"books",
			"in",
			"Torah"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Exodus[10]  This last of the ten plagues was the most deadly and persuaded the Pharaoh to let Moses and his people out of Egypt. The Israelites marked their doorposts with lamb's blood to avoid this plague.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round14.docx | 8 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]   Name this book that follows Genesis and describes the flight of the Israelites from Egypt. In this book, Moses destroys the golden calf that the Israelites worshipped and acquires the Ten Commandments on Mt. Sinai.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Exodus",
			"10",
			"This",
			"last",
			"ten",
			"plagues",
			"was",
			"most",
			"deadly",
			"and",
			"persuaded",
			"Pharaoh",
			"to",
			"let",
			"Moses",
			"his",
			"people",
			"out",
			"Egypt",
			"The",
			"Israelites",
			"marked",
			"their",
			"doorposts",
			"with",
			"lamb's",
			"blood",
			"avoid",
			"this",
			"plague"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Rastafarianism (or Rastas)[10]  In a Reasoning ceremony, a circle of Rastafari sit and smoke this drug in order to communicate with their god.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round15.docx | 1 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this religion originating in Jamaica, whose adherents follow the ital (\"eye-tal\") diet and typically have dreadlocks. Bob Marley was a notable proponent of this religion.",
		"answers": [
			"Rastafarianism",
			"Rastas",
			"10",
			"In",
			"Reasoning",
			"ceremony",
			"circle",
			"Rastafari",
			"sit",
			"and",
			"smoke",
			"this",
			"drug",
			"in",
			"order",
			"to",
			"communicate",
			"with",
			"their",
			"god"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Revelation (or Revelation of St. John; or Apocalypse of John; do not accept \"Revelations\" in place of \"Revelation\")[10]  Revelation begins by addressing this number of churches in Asia and then details the opening of this many seals, the sounding of this many trumpets, and the rising of a beast with this many heads.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "LIST (Ladue Invitational Spring Tournament) |2012 | LISTIII_Round16.docx | 18 | Religion |  | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question:  [10]  Identify this text written by John of Patmos, which details the Second Coming of Christ and is generally agreed to be the last book of the Bible.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Revelation",
			"St",
			"John",
			"Apocalypse"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "pagodas [or tǎ; or buttō; or tōba][10] This Hindu destroyer god with a third eye can be worshipped by pouring perfume or honey onto a stone stump  called a linga.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 1 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 1. Answer these questions about vertical objects used to venerate divine beings in Eastern religions, for 10 points  each. [10] These multi-story, multi-roofed towers are commonly built to serve as Buddhist temples in China and Japan.",
		"answers": [
			"pagodas",
			"tǎ",
			"buttō",
			"tōba",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Hindu",
			"destroyer",
			"god",
			"with",
			"third",
			"eye",
			"can",
			"be",
			"worshipped",
			"by",
			"pouring",
			"perfume",
			"honey",
			"onto",
			"stone",
			"stump",
			"called",
			"linga"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "pagodas [or tǎ; or buttō; or tōba][10] This Hindu destroyer god with a third eye can be worshipped by pouring perfume or honey onto a stone stump  called a linga.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl  |2012 | 1 | 1 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: 1. Answer these questions about vertical objects used to venerate divine beings in Eastern religions, for 10 points  each. [10] These multi-story, multi-roofed towers are commonly built to serve as Buddhist temples in China and Japan.",
		"answers": [
			"pagodas",
			"tǎ",
			"buttō",
			"tōba",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Hindu",
			"destroyer",
			"god",
			"with",
			"third",
			"eye",
			"can",
			"be",
			"worshipped",
			"by",
			"pouring",
			"perfume",
			"honey",
			"onto",
			"stone",
			"stump",
			"called",
			"linga"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Sufism [accept tasawwuf][10] The Mevlevi order of Sufism practices this as a form of Sama, or observance of dhikr. Sufis in the Western  world are often known for performing this action, which resembles the motion of a dreidel.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 2 | 13 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Answer some questions about Islamic mysticism, for 10 points each: [10] Practitioners of this form of Islam often perform dhikr, the repeating of the name of God. Its many schools span  the entire Muslim world, and its followers are sometimes called dervishes.",
		"answers": [
			"Sufism",
			"tasawwuf",
			"10",
			"The",
			"Mevlevi",
			"order",
			"practices",
			"this",
			"as",
			"form",
			"Sama",
			"observance",
			"dhikr",
			"Sufis",
			"in",
			"Western",
			"world",
			"are",
			"often",
			"known",
			"for",
			"performing",
			"action",
			"which",
			"resembles",
			"motion",
			"dreidel"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Gospel According to Luke [accept Gospel of Luke][10] The Gospel of Luke contains this statement, that one should do unto others what he would have others do unto  him.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 3 | 2 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This book contains the text of the Magnificat hymn. For 10 points each: [10] Name this Synoptic Gospel that shares much of its content with that of Mark, and which is the third of the  canonical gospels. It also contains the story of the Good Samaritan.",
		"answers": [
			"Gospel",
			"According",
			"to",
			"Luke",
			"10",
			"The",
			"contains",
			"this",
			"statement",
			"that",
			"one",
			"should",
			"unto",
			"others",
			"what",
			"he",
			"would",
			"have",
			"him"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Book of Deuteronomy [accept Devarim or Eleh ha-devarim][10] ] The speeches in Deuteronomy were given by this figure, who battled with the Amalekites along with Joshua and his brother Aaron. He led the Jews on the Exodus and received the Ten Commandments on Mount Sinai.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "Prison Bowl |2012 | 5 | 17 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: This book contains the Shema, a phrase recited in Jewish prayer services. For 10 points each: [10] Name this fifth book of the Torah, which contains speeches given before the entry of the Jews into the Promised Land. Its Hebrew name means \"these are the words\" and  it puts forth many of the Torah's laws.",
		"answers": [
			"Book",
			"Deuteronomy",
			"Devarim",
			"Eleh",
			"ha-devarim",
			"10",
			"The",
			"speeches",
			"in",
			"were",
			"given",
			"by",
			"this",
			"figure",
			"who",
			"battled",
			"with",
			"Amalekites",
			"along",
			"Joshua",
			"and",
			"his",
			"brother",
			"Aaron",
			"He",
			"led",
			"Jews",
			"Exodus",
			"received",
			"Ten",
			"Commandments",
			"Mount",
			"Sinai"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shinto [or kami-no-michi][10] Along with Shinto, this branch of Buddhism plays a major role in Japanese culture. Unlike its \"smaller vehicle\" counterpart, adherents of this branch venerate bodhisattvas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 10 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many Japanese identify themselves as members of multiple religions. Answer some questions about those religions, for 10 points each. [10] This religion, native to Japan, is polytheistic, and incorporates the veneration of spirits known as kami. Holy places in this religion include shrines like Kizomizu, and feature tori gates. Deities venerated in this religion include Susanoo and Ame-no-Uzume.",
		"answers": [
			"Shinto",
			"kami-no-michi",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with",
			"this",
			"branch",
			"Buddhism",
			"plays",
			"major",
			"role",
			"in",
			"Japanese",
			"culture",
			"Unlike",
			"its",
			"smaller",
			"vehicle",
			"counterpart",
			"adherents",
			"venerate",
			"bodhisattvas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Shinto [or kami-no-michi][10] Along with Shinto, this branch of Buddhism plays a major role in Japanese culture. Unlike its \"smaller vehicle\" counterpart, adherents of this branch venerate bodhisattvas.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 1 | 10 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Many Japanese identify themselves as members of multiple religions. Answer some questions about those religions, for 10 points each. [10] This religion, native to Japan, is polytheistic, and incorporates the veneration of spirits known as kami. Holy places in this religion include shrines like Kizomizu, and feature tori gates. Deities venerated in this religion include Susanoo and Ame-no-Uzume.",
		"answers": [
			"Shinto",
			"kami-no-michi",
			"10",
			"Along",
			"with",
			"this",
			"branch",
			"Buddhism",
			"plays",
			"major",
			"role",
			"in",
			"Japanese",
			"culture",
			"Unlike",
			"its",
			"smaller",
			"vehicle",
			"counterpart",
			"adherents",
			"venerate",
			"bodhisattvas"
		]
	},
	{
		"answerText": "Deborah[10] This Nazirite Judge told Delilah, a Philistine spy, that his hair was the source of his prodigious strength; she then subsequently betrayed him by shaving his head.",
		"prompts": [],
		"heading": "BHSAT |2011 | 2 | 7 | Religion | None | HS",
		"subject": "Religion",
		"level": "HS",
		"question": "Question: Name some Biblical Judges, for 10 points each. [10] This Judge joined forces with the Israelite general Barak to take down the Canaanite general Sisera in battle. The writer of a namesake \"song,\" she gave judgments under a palm tree and was female.",
		"answers": [
			"Deborah",
			"10",
			"This",
			"Nazirite",
			"Judge",
			"told",
			"Delilah",
			"Philistine",
			"spy",
			"that",
			"his",
			"hair",
			"was",
			"source",
			"prodigious",
			"strength",
			"she",
			"then",
			"subsequently",
			"betrayed",
			"him",
			"by",
			"shaving",
			"head"
		]
	}
]